Lynde Dupuy McCormick Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Lynde Dupuy McCormick Papers 1909-1959 (bulk 1952-1954)
MSS31971
McCormick, Lynde Dupuy, 1895-1956
3,600 items
16 containers plus 2 classified and 5 oversize
6.26 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Naval officer. Correspondence, reports, notes, scrapbooks, photographs, clippings, and miscellaneous printed matter relating primarily to McCormick's duty as Supreme Allied Commander Atlantic, 1952-1954. Includes trip reports and subject files relating to the countries of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
McCormick, Lynde Dupuy, 1895-1956.
Organizations
North Atlantic Treaty Organization.; Supreme Allied Commander Atlantic.
Subjects
Sea-power--Europe.; Sea-power--United States.; Security, International.; World politics--1945-1989.
Places
Europe--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Europe.
Occupations
Naval officers.
Provenance
The papers of Lynde Dupuy McCormick, naval officer, were given to the Library of Congress by McCormick in 1959.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Lynde Dupuy McCormick are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Security Classified Documents
Government regulations control the use of security classified material in this collection. Manuscript Division staff can furnish information concerning access to and use of classified materials.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Lynde Dupuy McCormick (1895-1956) span the years 1909-1959, with the bulk of the matierial dating from 1952 to 1954.. The collection consists of correspondence, reports, notes, scrapbooks, clippings, printed matter, photographs, and other papers relating chiefly to McCormick's duty as Supreme Allied Commander Atlantic, 1952-1954. Included are trip reports and subject files relating to the countries of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is organized by type of material.
Container List
- General correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1949-1951, Apr. (Box 1)
  - 1951-1959, May (Box 2)
- Personal file, 1909-1956 (Box 3)
- Speeches (Box 3)
- Subject file, clippings, and photographs (Box 4)
  - 1952-1954 (Box 4)
  - 1952-1954 (Box 5)
- Trip reports (Box 6)
  - 1952-1954 (Box 6)
  - 1952-1954 (Box 6)
  - 1952-1954 (Box 6)
  - 1952-1954 (Box 6B)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 7)
- Printed matter (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous printed matter and notes (Box 8)
- Photographs (Box 9)
- Photographs (Box 10)
- Photographs (Box 11)
- Photographs (Box 12)
- Photographs (Box OV 12A)
- Photographs (Box OV 13)
- Photographs (Box 14)
- Photographs (Box 15)
- Scrapbooks (Box OV 16)
- Scrapbooks (Box OV 17)
- Scrapbooks (Box OV 18)
- Classified (Box CL 1)
- Classified (Box CL 2)